{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost of five apples, four bananas and three chikkoos is Rs.50. If the cost of an apple, a banana and a chikkoo is Rs.12, how much more does an apple cost than a chikkoo?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A solution of alcohol and water contains 60% alcohol. What percent of the solution must be taken out and replaced with water, so that the resultant solution contains 40% alcohol?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>50%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='33' Height= '24' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACEAAAAYCAYAAAB0kZQKAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOhSURBVEhL1ZZdSJNRGMcXeKPmNCONMg01QTPNWZBkJYohWCkYeqE3kum0rvzcLKsFZYFQd259Yl5MESqNMr81ENey8rty7iY\/antF3bww8ePfOcczC7J4ZbvpB4P3+Z9z3v3f8zzneV8JHIhKpcL4+ASPxOMwEwX5+ZBItsBkNnFFPHabsFotkEVEICwsDJ6enhgeGeEj4rHbxPz8PJqbmzEtCNhOTAwMDPIR8TgsHabv3yF1c8Pg4BBXxOMwE9+mpuAulf7nJgwGA+RyOTIzM9HV9YYNUKanBZQqlcjIyEB1dTVXN2ZyYoKcDgk+fuzjyhorKyu4evUKUlJS8PDhI64CD+7fx3XVdXYt+fDhPVxdXHD6zBlcvHABTk5OaGpqxuLiInbv3oV9QUEoLCyEC5lz6dJltmgjLHNzKCgowOTkFFfWePb0Kby9d0LX0wNXV1f09fUzYzuJRv+HInnd2Ijs7BwWUMIOhCI3Lw+zMzNISkqCIEwzvVSpgI\/PHna9GRQlxYiNi2PXgQEBeF7fAHVlJWJj1zTKek0M9PdDoVDA19cXw8O\/zrogmFFRUcF0rbaGq+JpqK8nO+qDzs5OeO3wgl7\/DvtDQjBqGOMzfjOhVlN3sfDy9kZ7RwdXgS6yODExkTWiO3fvclU8q6urKC8vR2pqKlpaWqEkD3ou6zze9\/YiLS0NGs29P08HnSSVurPFv9PW2soKb2TkE4tramqQR9L2tx\/dVavVyubaWFhYICn1QQ+pDz8\/P9TW1uLwoUOQaLValJWV8WmARq3GVtJ09Ho90tPTsbS0xHTj2BgzoX\/Xy2KTyQSj0fjPn22tjbzcXGTnyDE0OAAPj21MU5SUQEJzRm9+7ZoK1U+esFNQVFxCakFgelJyMurq6hAaGoqICBmWl5fZ4s1iMIzCw92DnR4zecm5kQft7u7GiePH19LxoqEBUVFRkMlkuHHj5voT0N04GR+PyMhIZGVlkcUC0zeCbvW\/0GjUUJaW8gh4\/PgREhIScOvW7T9rYrM0vnqJ4OBgBPj7s5t+\/TrOR8Rjlwlbl8yR55Im1IeoI0dwNPoYHxWPXSYsFgurcBtFpLOGhx\/kkXjsTgeFNrpj0dFsV3S6t1wVj0NMGI1jqKqqwinS1GJiYkiR\/uAj4rDLBD1Fs7OzPCIt3mxmu9HW1s4Vcdhl4q1OB2dn5\/VviCbyMqQmPn\/+wmKx2J2Os+Q7ISAwkLyJs7GXtGLa9DYH8BONtgv+CVJyNgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='30' Height= '25' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAB4AAAAZCAYAAAAmNZ4aAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOtSURBVEhLpZZbMNRRHMeXtmjkmnXvIpfVmMykB8SDFw1GPRSWppSmXtC49dSFXZdJKqWGrQdPRtJDPdJgjJVYIaTk2miiMYwHlrSsb+ecOZaNsevvM3PG+X3\/Z\/\/f\/znn9zuHCAIZGhxEZkYGUlNTUVxcDK12mT8xDUHGU1NTOHL4MGJj41BaWgovLy8kJCTyp6YhyPhB0X24urnzCPjQooJIJMLXbwNcMY4gY838PGZmZngEVL96xYwnf\/\/minEE7\/Ea3V1dMDczQ26unCumsSvjutpaWOzbh7S0m1wxHcHGb2pqYG6+By9evuTKztAba\/\/+RXt7O1ZXV7liyMTEBO+RmdbVsj29e+8eJicnMTQ0hEFSXkvkHRStVgulUomKigqsrKwwjdJQX4\/mZhXr641l8fGwsbUjA3VcWefqlSQc8\/LmEXAtORkeHocQGBgIqVSqb8MjI+x5YkICoqKjceH8ech4mc2ThHRwcEB9fQOLRT09PYgmg+gMvL19oNMZzvh1dTV7JpX6cQVYXFxks1pYWDBoOp0OGo0GVlZWGPg+iK\/9\/bC03M9+o5DLERkZxfoUkZwIOTk5kOfmQCJxMjAeGx2Fk0SCsNBQ+Pj6cnV7lv78gbW1NdTqDqjb2+DoKMHEr1+wt7cndf6Nj9qw1CWPH8POzt7A+LifHwoKCqEsL4OzswtXjVNYkI+goCCEh4ejvFyJjPR0JCZeZPmjUqnYaumNHxQVka9ygI4nV1ZWJoKDQ1j\/0cNiuLq6sf74+DhLpq3a7OwsG0Npa2vDp85OzExPw93dHb29vQgLC4VMJkNMTMxmY8pP8nK6r\/7+\/oiIiICnpycsLCzIHkWymqUXw1athpTY\/yRdvoTbt++Q060KR496Mu10SIihMV1quhw0A9+9fYuqqipWEufOnSX7ZoPKyko+2jT6v\/TB1taWvE9DtvIRTgQEMP0MmYzeOD8vD2Lx3k1ZTclTyHHggDWPTIPW76nAk0hJSWVxh1pNEs2RXaEB5AP0xmNjY2hsbCQz5sIGRoaH0dTUxCOSuUtLBmVEY9poOa1BS66srAxzc\/NcAT62tkKhUJD97ls33gm3srP1hwbNA\/rXxcWFfPwPPsI4gozpMUmPSNo+d3fDkiTe9es3sLy8fjwaQ5DxRtJINruRfwq2Omq3Y1fGfaQ2adnV1b3niunsyjg+Lpad70IQbLxALgOxWIzSZ8+5sjMEG7eQM5cu8wi5SIQg2PjpkxIcPOjIo50C\/ANq518tCGQ7RgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='28' Height= '26' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAaCAYAAACkVDyJAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAN7SURBVEhL1ZZbSFRRFIaPBqapZI09eEnQERHtwZryRcow1EB7kqweLJpSA62xhAwczQt2VXvQgkqsLIMMvHWxi1CUIJhUapSXcaZGw7ujIc5gjn\/7rNlipMY5PgR9cGCvtdfhP2vtvdc+AlZAfl4eXrx4yS15yBYsLS2Bvb09bt+p4B55SBYcHh5GWFgY3BXucHR0ZMJX+Yw8JAv29vZCq9VieGgIbmvXorComM\/IQ3ZJ5+ascGIZFhVf4R55yBa0WMxY4+T0HwparVaMjIxwa3lEQcfVq5ddw+bmZvT09HDLhtFohF5voDEJNja+hFKphJeXFwIDA\/Hq9WuaXApRcBU7FpcuF3LPAklJiQgP3wmVSoXy8lvkm5mZga+vL2pr68gW+pj6Ojc3aLOy0N3djd3R0XBxdcX09DQF\/IlYidbWVgwMDHCPjW9fv8LOzg4jo2O4eeM6Nm70If+1q6UICdlMYxGh6e0bCIIAHdv2IpX37pI9MTFJtlTaPn6Eg4MDjevqauHh4QmzeZqq9uz5c\/KLCFbrLE6dTENw8CZoNBp4enoiI+MMn5aOxWKB0s8Publ52BMbgxOaNFwpLsLmLSoeYUMQA1NTUqgEcXFxcGPl1bDgn7OzPEQ6Br0eycnJyM\/Px+joKGXX8u4dsrOzEBMTg5KSUgjF7CvWr1fAZJqglz51dFBJq6oekl1dXU2ZL\/ekp6djfHycYn8n52w29u6NRz0rr7v7BrS3t8Nf6Q8hhWWnUm3lYTac2DkrKDhHY51Oh5aWlr8+ZrOZYucRP0ChUEBvMECbmYntO8LJHx0VBeFZQwNllJOTi66uLhw7lkx2Z2cnBa2EQwcTEBGxi8aXL12k5ZqamkJwUJDtHN6vrIS3tzd8fHwQxJw1NTUUvBIGBwcREBCAtrZ2sk0mE9tEsYiMjERq6vGFTjPLNslSazHPj8lJXDh\/Hmq1GjfLyrh3MeImFLP5k\/lzK6mXjo2Nwd9fSWcrMTERrqwx7N9\/gDWBOR4hHUmCH96\/Z90iBH3938luePqE1tlo7CNbDpIEf8fAdp5afRjbQkMX7U4pyBJsamqiJi9mV\/QvbnyxoYv\/NlUPHpDo\/A0gB0mColB\/fz+3bLg4O+P0afk9V5Lg40f1lNHnL7ZmoGMXrGhXVNwlWw6SS7ovPp4OdEJCAl2oR44c5TNyAH4Bjj4XDrNaQ3AAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Three runners, A, B and C, run around a circular track of 180 m length in 12, 15 and 18 seconds respectively. If they start running at the same time and in the same direction, from the same point on the track, find the difference between the time taken by them to meet for the first time ever and the time taken by them to meet for the first time at the starting point. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>120 seconds\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>60 seconds\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>180 seconds\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A four-digit number is such that the sum of the first two digits is equal to the sum of the last two digits, while the sum of the first and the third digit is equal to the last digit. If the sum of the first and the last digits is thrice the sum of the second and the third digits, which of the following can be the second digit of the number?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are 42 students in a class. Each student plays one, two, three, four or five games. The number of students who play at most one and at most two games is 8 and 21 respectively, while 12 students play at least four games. How many students play exactly three games?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"9","CORRECT_ANSWER":"9","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Coyote was 700 m behind Roadrunner when they both started running in the same direction. If Coyote's speed is 35 kmph and Roadrunner's speed is 28 kmph, find the time taken by Coyote to overtake Roadrunner.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 minutes\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 minutes\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 minutes\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6 minutes\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the remainder when 3<sup>1<\/sup><sup>0<\/sup><sup>0<\/sup> is divided by 30?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>21\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost prices of two varieties of rice differ by Rs.12. Ram, a shopkeeper, mixes these two varieties in a certain ratio and the resultant mixture costs Rs.18 per kg. If instead, Ram mixes the two varieties in the inverse ratio, the cost price of the resultant mixture will be Rs.26 per kg. Find the cost price (in Rs.<\/font><font style='font-family:Rupee Foradian;'> <\/font><font style='font-family:Arial;'>per kg) of the less expensive variety of rice.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"16","CORRECT_ANSWER":"16","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A trader marked a watch 40% above the cost price and then gave a discount of 10% while selling it. If he made a net profit of Rs.468 after paying a tax of 10% on the gross profit, find the cost price (in Rs.<\/font><font style='font-family:Rupee Foradian;'>) <\/font><font style='font-family:Arial;'>of the watch.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"2000","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2000","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The number of natural numbers <i>n<\/i> such that  <img Width='47' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAC4AAAAfCAYAAACYn\/8\/AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAVUSURBVFhH7ZhrTFRHFMcX6BeiKFQaAiZaPok8Wgs0KY9WyxtBaUhNABssYCIBjFUBW\/ygRVAqjyhoQaoJ7PLQKkIFyrMUishDiv3QBTRQaSTIUuhSntIFTmfODrte9u6y27iaJv0lk53\/mbl3\/zs7d+bMFQAP3d3d0NbWxpT+WFxchKKiIpibm2MROb1iMcTGxkJcXBwkJ58h\/ZZYixIV42LxrxAbEwuLS6qd9cGPTU2QmHiCKTmuLi6QlHQS+vv7wd7eHkSiItaihGN8amoKHB0doY9c8DI5dvQzOHQoGutLZMBaW1uxTnF3c4OU1LNMKeEYP5mUBD6+fkzpj\/n5eZDJZEwBjI2NgampKfT1cQcsNSUF3NzcYXZ2lkWUKIzTm20wMYErV\/JZRD+0t9+DLVu2QEdHJ4vIedfZGcIPHGAKyHSNgaCgjzg\/8HkUxpt+aASBQAD3u39mkRdPZeUdMDQ0wO9pa7vHonKo0Y0bTdHovn0fw9atb8JPZMq0t7fD0NDvrJcShfHUlDN4Qwn52yglJSVQKBRCamoq+Pr6QkJCIkgkEmzj49mzeSguLoaFhQUW4VIkEoGxsTEZxSBe47lfX8Z4T08PhISEQFhYGAQHB2P\/0tLrrJcShfED4eF44cTEBGpPDw\/UO3a8A+GszdfPH9v4kEr\/BGfyd9MHnA8xWeIGBgag+34Xr3GRSIjxhsZGFtGMwvgn+8PwwvHxcdS7\/f3AzOx1kJG1lvLF5ydg3XoTrKvD31\/9D1uhvq6W17iwsBDjtbV1LKIZhfGw0FCOcS8y4g4Ob2GdkpGeDps2mTOl5MKFC2TNTYLjx4+BtbU1xMfHo87JyWE9uDTU12k0XlNTyyKaURhPTIjHC\/9gxr09PcHW1g7rlLRz53iNd3Z2QhPZROiD5+TkBNXV1ai7urpYDy5rGX\/w4BcW0YzC+I0b1\/FCsbgXtceuXbBtmw3WKWfJQ2pqasaUKjLZ3+Dt7Q3Ly8ssws\/KVLl7l5tSJH95GoyMXlP7jKxGYVwiGcUbfnvzFmofLy+ws7PHOuWrtDQwN3+DKVUmJ6VofHp6mkX4oSNuYGCgMuJ7AgPB3f19ptZGYZyyd+8eCA0Nw\/rwkydk\/RzCOoWuNgMDg0ypQrfq4eFh\/NQE3QUfPXpEEqt5FpFjZWkJ3925w9TacIz39fbCZqvNiiXxZVFVWQku77kwpR0c45TLly5BVNRBtRvJi2b06VPY+cFOkkrrtmOrGKfQXbOlpYUp\/fJNfj7ulroioLsZNUq365VSXl4OBQUFnJg+ioikAbRUVFTwtqsrZWVlIKCnnczMTMjIyFAUqrOysjgxfZR\/+z3Z2dn8U+W\/wP\/GXzavxDjdqHzILutFdmdafHx8MAfXZRl+JcbHxiRw+PBhfP1Ay5EjRzDdeJvk\/uqOaqvRynhnRwc0NDRAVVUVvu+gqaxUKmWt\/DQ3N8PMzAxTmsnLzQUTkw0wMjLCImujlfHIiE9xRCwsLEgi5I71Dz088YWOOlxdXWFw8Dem1DP0+DHeL0\/HQ7pWxmOiozGj63\/4EHX6+fP4ZVLpJGo+Akm2J5X+xZR69pOzpaWl1Zrp8Gq0Mh4VEYHHuBXKbt3E3Hm18du3b8PFixex2NjYwKlTp7F+9eo13rk7OipPpbOz+U9LmtDK+MHISDS+tCQfldKSYl7j9fX1IBQKsTg4OJCdMQvrN0mOL5OpTqv8K3lofHxc92xU6xGnp5\/njRsaGmmcKgEBASQ91vwABwbshu3bbZnSDa2MHyXLlRXJ01eo+b4a1q1bzxQ\/9J3I1JTm05C9nR3ExMYxpQsA\/wCnDPI0aOZBKQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  is an integer is\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A van travels 10 km on one litre of diesel and the price of diesel was Rs.22 per litre. After servicing, it gives 10% extra mileage (i.e., km travelled on one litre of diesel). If the price of diesel also now goes up by 15%, how much more than earlier would it cost now to cover one km?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>15 paise\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>22 paise\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20 paise\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10 paise\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Which of the following values is the highest?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='62' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAD4AAAAQCAYAAABOZ8wCAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAARzSURBVFhHxZZbLKVXFMePiIQHiUanBk8k03Q8OFOadLy4RUiVEQQ1h6dB0mFSMvpC45K4nPGCB4mkxbiMRp26NKVExgPTxi1j0Ij7cDCl00QznLr791vrbM75znDO6ND5JTvZ\/7X3t79v7W\/ttZcCb0BFRQVSU1MttsLCQhweHoqnLp6NjQ2kpaWd+u7zNouO7+\/vw8\/PDz09Pejt7TXbxsfHxVOXQ3NzM+Li4k5993laX1+fZcfpZYmJiUK9W1QqFdra2oR6Oyw6np6ejvLycqHeHRR5\/v7+WF1dFZa3w6LjwcHBGB0dFQrY3NzE2NgYtFqtsPw\/0DeEhIQIZWBqagrb29tCGZifn+ejt7OzIyxyzDq+srKCgIAA7O3tsW5oqMd7Dg6ws7ODtbU1VAkJ2N3Vj102FHUZGRlC6SkvK4WVlRXGxieERR8ZcbGxUCgUsLGxgYuLC578+psYNWDW8draWiQlJXH\/mbTjtFhMTCwWF5fQ2trCOic3j8cvm5iYGHR2dnKffkR+Xh6\/n9rExO9sJ\/LzctnW3KzB7OwslJ6eeP\/KFWxt6cQMPWYdT0lJQXV1NfcXFub5ujJewMXZGb5+\/kKZZ2RkBEtLS0KdD51OB19fX77OCH\/plnF0dMTt+HiZ40eHR7jq5ITPQj9nTQwPDfKcnzs6hEXPmY4fHR0hKCgI09PTwmJgYGAAmffvw1ly\/PHjXmE1j0p1W9rEGqHOR39\/P8LCwrh\/cHCA+vp6aRP+RtcvnTLH\/3r5knVBQSFr4s\/1dbYVqx8Ii54zHZ+bm0NgYOBrBcmylNSuX\/+Iz\/i1ax9K4TQnRsxz9+6X0GhahDofRUVFyMrKEspA46MGmePr62usC4uKWRN\/vHjBNvWDEmHRo1hbW+PEoVQq0dXVJcxAZWUlVzim7O7uchalnfzE2wtOTlel8N8So3KGh4fRIYUYNcrImZlfn+jnzxfFLAMzMzNcmXl7e\/PGHxMZGcmFhynfNz6SOU6+8N8tVrMm1k+xEYrGxkbk5+fD1dUVbm5uJxmcipampibuE2SnUDKmteVHXvTpU8N1ZwytnZuby83LywtRUVEnemBwUMwyoFarkZ2dzWuGhoayjc41nW8656aYOv7q1SuOROOEe\/zHy8rktchJqFPGpAmlpaWsqVhYXl7mPlH13bewtbWVzvyMsAAZUnFDz2i1hnlnce9eqlR1tQtlnoKCAl6XImZoaAjR0dFiRI6p48QNpSeUNz4WCnhYU8NzRkefCYse2RmnM013dHd3NyIiIoRVj1bKyB9I1wIlNPozSXfu8ILZ2d+IGeaJj\/8CVVX6G8ISVHTQ\/evj48Nnu6REfj6PeVhTLZwaExbgp\/Z2tt26FYGcnBzuG2f5Y2SOT05O8kQHqUih8DdlYWEBCVLR4uHhgU9v3kRtXZ0YsUxdXS3fBm+KRqPhb6EiZGLCUKAYMzQ4gOTkZKnQkpexP0hHlDaNvvMrKSp1un\/EiIHXsjo5bG9v\/5\/v3IskPDwc7u7uQl0kwL\/aAYgmG+6ozQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='60' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADwAAAAQCAYAAABKkhw\/AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQ2SURBVFhHzZZpSFxXFMdHKiIYcUFSTLR0VNzQqB9cEGqFuoLzRWwxNWKD4BLBaGw1VXBrlbrgB1MUkphiClonKmIQbFyqoojLJ1GQUdHG2rh0OnHf\/ffdM3fUUccZLRF\/cOGdc+597553zzn3iKADGxsbSE9PR1JSkk6jqqqKr\/zwjI6OnrkHTUMnhzs6OuDh4YHOzk6dxszMDF\/54UlMTERcXNyZ+zg5uru7dXM4MjISeXl5XLo+7OzswN7enk5ZV7Q6vL+\/DwcHBwwNDXHN9aG\/vx\/Ozs60R13R6nBfX5\/aS\/f29rCysoLl5eXDsbm5SbarJjMzE9HR0VxSMjU1hZGREWxo2JNWh1mxiomJ4RKQmvIQ5ubmMDU1PRwpKancerX4+vqitraWntmPl0jCIBKJYGBgAEtLS9RJX5HtOFod9vLyQkNDA5eAT6yt8UVAAHp7e2n09PRgYmKCW6+OxcVF2NjYYH5+nuT0774lZ5ubX2NychIhIcH4SF8fCwsLZFdxrsNzc3MQi8VQKBQkLy0t0Ut\/q5OSfBnYFcd+0sHBAddcjpqaGjphFZ\/7fYabNz\/mEvBKWkd7HR0b4xol5zpcWVmJAOE0VXR1\/UEvYTr2I1xcXPDs+XNu1Y23b\/+Et7c31YL\/Q1RUFLKysrgE4crpgrWVFeLj41FRUQFnJydEfPnVqfpyrsMSiQSlpaVcAn558YIcjoiIoObi\/v1vSP6pqIjP0M779woEBwdz6XLs7u7CSXBoYGCAa4B37\/6Gu9sd6OnpwUpwnO3ryZOfufUIEcuB8vJyODo6orCwkKuVoWdnZ4fx8XGuAdbW1jAl5MdxQoKCcOOGMba3d7jmNKurq2hpaaFRXV0Nd3d3IdeaSX7T1kYOnIVMJkNaWhrtTSo9SqPh4WG6KlVRsr29LfwAR3wqRN3s7F+ke\/b0KTnd2vo7ySpELBcKCgrg5uZGEwYHB8nQ3t4OV1dXelbBPnAyFL9\/nEHr1oUfpAmW+7k5OcgRxqNHqVRssrOzSS4qLsbW1hafeQS7Btm1k5+fDzMzMxgbG0Mul5ONHUx4eDg9M+Tyf3ikFXONEhMTE0TdU7+2DkN6TEhuFg4qJ5OTk6n3PM4DoY27fdtKbYM+Qj6KxTYaT+kk6+trCA0N5ZJuNDY2kkOxsbEk+\/v7q\/Xrq0JfwOyRd7\/mGlB1Zv5kZDzmGiVqOZybm0sLS0pK4OfnhzYh3I7T1vaG7K6ud2hOaEgIya2trXyGdljR8vT0vHDRCgwMpG81NTVRNLIb5DgFP\/7Anb5LEXDrliUsLCyE783yGUrUHGa5wE6YLbS1tSX5JKwJDwsLo+4rKChYqNzd3KIbCsW\/KCsru1A7yGD5rC\/cq4aGhhqL3q8vX8LHx4f2dk\/owGSy0\/3BqSo9PT1N3VNCQgLXXB9YcTUyMkJ9fT3XXBTgPyiZKz1RbqkNAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='49' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADAAAAAPCAYAAACiLkz\/AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAN4SURBVEhLvZZLLFxRGMfHgghFpSKhC7qpVFjRlY2JSjwj8QxdSCwqoWoGbcNIJHRBIlIzRqs0sSBRNoqRtMQjQmw84h0TCzae8ZwSz3\/v+ebcuejcGwv1S77k\/L9z7j3nu\/N93xkVFLi4uEBZWRm0Wq2ijY6O8ifuj+3tbWg0Grv7iVZaWgrFACYnJ5GYmIjV1VVFOzs740\/cH42NjXRIe\/uJtra2phxAcXExqquruXpYkpKSMDg4yJU8igEkJCRgZGSEq4fj8PAQarUa+\/v73COPbAD2XrKxvo6xsTEsm83c838YHx9HfHw8jbe2trAu7Cva5uYm+c7Pz2leNoCBgQH6GUW+NzXB0dERrq6uUKlUyMt7h6urKz57v9TU1ECn09E4MPAF3N3dyTw9PeHt7U3nWFlZoXnZACorK20vmZubo0OXl1fg6OgIxro60kPDwzR\/32RkZKC7u5vGi4uLmJmZIZuYmICX1xPExMbZGodsAOnp6ejp6aFxYUEB\/Pz8acwqf3d3F1NTU9jb2yOfHL2mHjQ0fOPqbpyenlLqbmxscI\/Exw\/v4eHxGBbLH+6RCeDk5IResrOzQzouNgb+\/s\/wMjSUUsjFxUU4WAPNKWE06JGTk8vV3ZidnUVUVBRXEublZfrVW1pauccKBcAKo6urixwM9nWjo6O5AtTh4fRwSYkOZqGAP1VUWFNo6N8UYnXBCozZ1y\/1wmWktenLy0u+SqKvrw9Go5ErIWhhnJ+fz5VEakoKfH2fciWhYsWamppKB2pttUZnMBjoEhF5FREBn1sPs1zUaAu4kpgX6iUrK4ssLCwMQUFBNv3rdx9fZYV9tJCQENp7mNdTZmYm2tvbaSyyI9zKbM3nWj33SKhYrlksFiQnJ8PHx4ecbLOOjg4aM7SafCF1HnFlxd3NTSjyUq4k2N8PVujMDPpa6laivn1js7Z4fHyMUCE1WSCMyMhIW4cR+dHWRgGsCvV3G1sNsNRgi5qbm5GWlnbjJQsL83AQ5mJiYtHf34\/XQpdwcHAQutM8X2GfemMdcnPfciUP+\/psb\/bLsw95uz2z\/VyE2rPHjSJmncfJycl2iVyn12RCcHAw9eLnAQEw9fbyGXl+dnZCrzdwpQxrGiwIsXVfp6ioEG+ys7m6yY0ADg4O4OzsjKqqKu55OJaWluiSmp6e5p67APwF3E7gBgsm00oAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='53' Height= '16' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADQAAAAQCAYAAABZRVzLAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAPQSURBVEhLxZZLLJxRFMcHCQ0iUREiaqWJaptgox5J1StY6EJpKxJvERLS1oZ4JAy6qCY0IakxIsGYYKUabZBWXxIsvB8RZUbJWHQSM0KNOL3nzP3G+xuail9yM\/d\/7us7d+4590rADIODg5Cbm2u2FBUVgcFg4KP+P0ql8tR1jxezDiUkJEBLSws5JlbGxsb4iMshOjoaenp6Tl1bKENDQ+IOraysQFhYGFdXx\/DwMMTGxnIljqhDHR0dkJqaytXVUVtbCwUFBVyJI+pQXl4e1NfXc3WUra0t2NnZ4epySUtLo80VwHUnJiZApVJzywGiDkVFRdHA40wym5ubG9u5Om65PDDRREREsI9Xke7u6gIXFxewtrYGOzs7SE\/PgL29PWpDznRIrVZT\/BzPXLu7f8D7lhdIJBKorn7JrZfHwsICOYT8XFoCK0tLuB\/yABYXF2FgYIC+49nzF9SOnOkQpsnk5GSuDkhPTwNHx+tgw3ao6pwOra6uwsjICFcXo7W1FTIyMqj+pq6OHFCrV0kjpcXFYGlpBXq9nvSZDuXn55+IH6Wygyb8\/v0HXLtmA+UVUt4ijqK9ndL\/v5CTkwMymYzqr2te0fqbmzrSiKzxLdnm5+dJmxzSarW8ZiQmJuZI\/KhUKzSwSd5MGuvSyiqqm+N9by9kZWVxdTEiIyNhZmaG6t++faV1CwuNl\/jy8jLc9PQk28zsLPWRTE9PQ0pKCjg5OcHo6CgZ8YiEh4eb4md7exvu+fuzu+Ahaa32N01SIa0kfRpra7+glzmCBV8RGAeCFtY5DMZEYmIiBAUFsX9gk2zr6+sQGhrK4naXNFJRXk5rOzs7g7u7O\/j5+YGFhQVzaI7aJX19fSCXy8He3h5CQkLI2N3dfSR++vv7aRJXV1eaBH9ROzg4QFzcI97rKFNTk1BWVkYFj5uPj49JKxQHKVigoaHB+HRh80qlxqOM35GUlET1w8yyf0OhUAD+GfKmJhojnDDTkaupqaGGubk5KGe7UMcCUECj0dCzo7OzkyaSyRqpb8Ljx5RpzPHxwwfIzs7mShw86ra2tpSKS0tL6bsEZtnRw6tEo9ngFoC7d26zzfKF\/f190iaH8KLEnQ8ICKBnxvj4OG85icGwSw6dNym0t7VBfHw8V+Jg3OLcJSUllN3wfSawsbFBzt7w8GBXRjUEBgZS3y9fvvIehxxCMEViBy8vL5PHp6HX6yAzMxPesXg4D\/hwbW42JpPzgDGN3+Hr60vxexjMZk+fPgFvb2+Ky0+fPvMWIyfSdnBwMO3OVaLT6ShJYTK5GAB\/AXl7WiLFbR4FAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  <b>\n<\/b><\/font><b>\n<\/b><\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A and B, each working alone, can do a certain piece of work in 40 days and 120 days respectively. A and B start working together on that work, but after having worked for 10 days, additional work came in. The additional work is such that B would take 40 days working alone to complete it. In order to cope with the additional load, C is inducted and the remaining work is finished in 5 days. Find the number of days that C alone would take to complete the original work.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>12\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9 \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A goat is tied to the corner of a rectangular plot, of dimensions 14 m \u00d7 7 m, with a rope 21 m long. Since there is a wall constructed all along the boundary of the plot, and the goat is tied outside the plot, it cannot graze inside the plot but can graze outside it, as far the rope permits. Find the approximate area (in sq.m) that the goat can graze.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1080\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1180\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1232\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1596\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A candidate gets a net score of 420. If he got as many wrong answers as the number of questions he left unattempted, how many questions did he answer correctly?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"86","CORRECT_ANSWER":"86","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"5506","EASSY_DETAILS":"<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i><b> <\/b><\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Answer the questions on the basis of the information given below.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">In a management entrance test, there are 150 questions. Six marks are awarded for each correct answer, two marks are deducted for each wrong answer and one mark is deducted for each question left unattempted.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","ESSAY_NAME":"D-X) Test name AIMCAT1922"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":"","ESSAY_NAME":""},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the total number of distinct scores that are possible, if a candidate attempts all the questions?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>150\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>151\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1200\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1201<i><b>\n<\/b><\/i><\/font><i><b>\n<\/b><\/i><\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"5506","EASSY_DETAILS":"<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i><b> <\/b><\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Answer the questions on the basis of the information given below.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">In a management entrance test, there are 150 questions. Six marks are awarded for each correct answer, two marks are deducted for each wrong answer and one mark is deducted for each question left unattempted.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","ESSAY_NAME":"D-X) Test name AIMCAT1922"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":"","ESSAY_NAME":""},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Two vertical wooden poles of heights 12 m and 27 m are located 8 m apart. If the shorter pole is chopped off at a distance of 4 m from the top, at what distance from its base should the taller pole be chopped off to ensure that the distance between the tops of the two poles remains the same? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>18 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>23 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>An arithmetic progression is given by 2, 4, 6, 8 \u2026\u2026.. upto <i>n<\/i> terms. If the sum of the last five terms and the first five terms of the progression is 130, find the sum of all the terms of the progression. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"156","CORRECT_ANSWER":"156","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the compound interest accrued on a certain sum, at 11% p.a, for two years is Rs.1064.8 more than the simple interest accrued on the same sum, at the same rate and for the same period, what is the sum?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.9,680 \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.8,800\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.80,000\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.88,000\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There is a set of three concurrent lines on an infinite plane. If a line is drawn parallel to one of these lines, what is the number of regions into which the plane is divided?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A certain distance is covered at an average speed of 20 km\/hr; 37.5% of the distance is covered at 15 km\/hr and another stretch comprising 12.5% of the distance, at 25 km\/hr. What is the average speed (in km\/hr) for the rest of the distance?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"25","CORRECT_ANSWER":"25","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If <i>f<\/i> (<i>x<\/i>) = 2<i>x<\/i> + 3, and <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>( <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>( <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(<i>x<\/i>))) = 13, then the value of <i>x<\/i> = \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-1.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-2.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhpACSAPcAAP\/\/\/0dHRyMjI93d3cPDw4mJiWlpaQAAAKenp7+\/v39\/f5eXl9fX14+Pj3d3d0BAQBgYGD8\/P2hoaCgoKC8vL09PT6+vr+\/v7x8fH3BwcIeHh+fn58\/Pzw8PDzg4OMfHx0hISFdXV9\/f33h4eLe3t1hYWPf392dnZyAgIJ+fn19fX56enmBgYCcnJzAwMKamplBQULa2tjc3N4aGhm9vb46OjgcHBwgICBoaGhISEl1dXaqqqiIiIlFRUa6urhAQEJaWlnl5eVRUVA4ODgICAmFhYbCwsLy8vBQUFAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAApACSAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjYgwgQKbNmwgHCBBAAKdPnAWCGvhJNKaAAQMOFF3KkkBNAAEQMJ0KIIFVBVizLrDKIKOBA2APBKCKk0EDBw8gHIjANmtWCWwnHKBQQYGFCxMP9ASQdADZlxcQSMAwIYOGBBsecrCgoEIHDxo+PESgdGCAAn9ZIgDRIcQCERk\/jPAAQULXhQGGDixQObNJBhIghCABcsOCCR4W4HWNk0OFCQsSk\/wwWMFu3i9FlKBgQeUFBRgamEDO8sIJFFJbXsiAIQX1lAiAy\/\/coALE6e8iN4AIIdwmCQoa0IdcMYH2TxOjQcvnmIHFcaIftJDAfhld8EADVKVwgAsIElgRBxQMOJUCLDyQQAYlTOdgRBxEoB9TLCgAgIUAvACDhhs2lEAE\/xFlAgjejShhDDC0mOJBJARgo08XeGCfjAPFwOKNCZFw4lQiuMABQSQO1OGON37wAIpFfeDChwI1OdAHEVBJpAgytFeUBQ\/YqOVAL5RA5EAXRLAkUwscaRALMRY0QnxrghDDVCNIkBCdCMHQ3I0OzMCUCSzgiRCgB5kwAZb7rcjUBTDUuailBXHp5XcXUAApThs88OOfmBaElYMsrLAUAx68uRCjCXn\/IJl8Kaiw1AcefHrpQiJMsGlmJmAgJk5kQnmQBAswdOp3hRbVgJwOLatQsMP+tQEGv8aUQQYSSatQmtRVMChOJpTQYETeKkSBq39B+NMFIGTXrYgNueuauD6JcCa69Da0bmbXZtsSBw+wO+9DFlSQGQ014JTAA7pClO5CE5x3qLA3bWbsQw1w+1ANNJC1gJ82NZBhRimwAJEJEGxs074uSeAxyipDpEKp+aIgkwkwJLtRyhGRAMJUM4wQk4HjagT0yi0z9W9ysnq0tM0428TABDBx4IHFP9cMkdBLdfwSCQ9Uq7TXD5nQgcAw4dtSCjWGBLZEEUj4Uwcui6QBC2xjwfTwRBPLdHVLEhg90t8SJUxUrSvx7PPhD0x0QQdEIeucB0mLhLhET+MUNUpJGqx55BOFIO9NEJgdEgdXorR5RHf6ZIINKJHgQd4dvQ4RAmr2RsFJKYDQ90eDT4SrT4qXRCFLIugsOeU4aWD4SCG21HxFqeMUOEcvVm3S9RShEHFLDij60QY+Juf8ROLjBKtHrIquEvgTfW7T+xzhOj7o69Ntt0wwy0ixZEI\/\/+EkgBeJ0\/BQ0hoD3sRtG+mTTxoYkbr\/uc97EkGU+WxCQYh0TiaWK1CliNLBh7TvJtuLSKhGhZMSOuSENknhQ+K3FBc2xIYtGdlFEpArpuBwWrRzWAQsorGp3GCBBrHXTTYAgYqYDIkvgSFEkocTG0CRINv6ixQfogEH\/KRiESnXuaiyRYeEECcQbAi8TkfG\/SXEgj6RYUH09T+ylLEhePuJpOpVMOTccSFKxMnkVAQx6vxRITokygcPEjzcEUVJErlZUTIwRoPs7Yo+QaBCDgkTKhqkcPvRJEJEgIGlqG1TjiOQKA8yAy8uBX9Ic9AqDWI\/l4QFLKebm0BEUEv5zJIgpJSJXgSSFHlRSyBa45ov67iQVgpz\/y8AKMBYBmI5sqnuO78cSC9bMkyBEKCBEIKbIzMjKMX87pkD+WZBcJADHaTgmtTBn0JMx0FoqpMgO+CBAHoAgcJYAJNEkSdCAlbP1UyTIBjwgQs0YBYY3OABkUGPQA9CyZt0MynQHEjH8LM1gSRgND8owWd4M9GCnNKit8zoQI5pJfMFRgIoQIEEEDDOl5SUIHJcnK0AgB8QVEsECyjBDzwwAmZekCEERU7nSDAB731AAw+4AQwaoMyY3FQg9KTO8djEAp9OywIZmAAE6ATPlMROIYFEThoBwFQMDmQDKYOACzJAAoB2RI6L5M0GKDCsC3S1rAThQANAcAMQaEB+yv\/r10HEth9dEoQELmBhQ0gwAheEdKQnSSEDKKChr4QFM645weMIoh7\/SE4wKJiABO5Cku2ZoFUDMYBqMOoaE1CgqgBIQX0swoA4DVUBs\/rI9ioaW9UAQABspIrWslXamiLkAwrwgFSpelfFBmloBJEtMQ\/gF95YAAYK0a1kKWICsE4ABSxAAGAbMjEGyKBFngULaJHD2IGCYAR2TYgIUlACudLVIlMTSKc+pV2BCGC+vDkBEBaiARcElyOCBcEBDIvY8KLNBAEwaoGjeVDe8GxPCmEVfuVWWQiUIAVuHEiAU4WQDR8YPR9mSIMffD4EsCC1q2Xb0hClqhbfssPUeVH\/j0NM1NfE6QYeAC4jVcazIa9pUU5OiAY6ehLoeuAHPTtPyng23icXhAUzU0hLnWMBCZw3vUGoQPq8zJAGDGkhHMUtSQgghCEQgQhF6DKbC5KAvB5kzCe5wAIegIIRBOEBRtAAYUHQgArvWQQRMBRDOJpijPDuBxJADAjCbAISZMAFJn7nng1yAQdQeSFWcmtFEsCCkGaHPnregI37mYF\/jiS+YHHJByYw4oX41asaYUAGUPCAFOyGVaZtSEMfGtGPbFiaL9FAUyc7bYtsoAETmEADPrSBDFCAxg\/56JV7VumHbNgpMBEBCyaQuYP8er0FuUAK0pIBiz0nOvklyAXK\/xzTmTr3IBve8EsYUAEKJNcgTD04QizQXxbUcQPQUUC+9RvUoRa1Irh+ik040F\/TKOQCJUj2cyWAZQR4aTMQMM5woFpY6kJE4D+xDW5czsjdFoQBCkBBbv7T6diUQM8h6XRYxypqhsC8SkNXAU0N0lwA2MYFE1AAliJsAxAEByZwZQGt65qQozMFriXogA0iIAEFWGVAugVBaY5gFQQ0hgJz+e9PzEJYiIrO62QxQQIWoIAH+P2WgA+84AdP+MIb\/vCDR8KoF8\/4xjv+8T75JliMC3nXUKa7l6k8b5A7kKRoPjN9+Tx1Qi963pC+9K7h\/Ha7i\/qlXF4gqWk9VSgzeQ3Z2\/72uM+97nfvkoAAADs=\" style=\"width: 164px; height: 146px;\" \/><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">In the figure above, PC is a tangent to the circle from the point P and B is a point on the circle such that PB = CB. Find <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Calibri;\"> <img height=\"12\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAMCAYAAABWdVznAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAADnSURBVChThZA9CoQwEIX3OnoAD2Bv6QG8hGdQEGvvYCFoJWhtZSNipWAjNloL\/r3dGUhw1132g5fJI\/MmIY\/zPEFQ\/dRxHKwrMvCPYRi4ysC+7zeJ6Y7jwLZt3v8MiGbP82BZFtZ1ZX8LbNsmm33fh2EYWJaFPfH1BiIIAmiahmma2NMg4hYgoiiCqqpo25b99ewtQBRFwZOrqmJPk0kycP3nuq6h6zrKsmQvJgsRMtB1HUzTRNM07H\/xoKXveyiKAtd1+Ul5nr8pTVPu4QDdMM8zwjBElmVIkgRxHHMVezobx\/HVDjwBP7YQLmkjHg4AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"12\" \/> <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">DCP, if <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Calibri;\"> <img height=\"12\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAMCAYAAABWdVznAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAADnSURBVChThZA9CoQwEIX3OnoAD2Bv6QG8hGdQEGvvYCFoJWhtZSNipWAjNloL\/r3dGUhw1132g5fJI\/MmIY\/zPEFQ\/dRxHKwrMvCPYRi4ysC+7zeJ6Y7jwLZt3v8MiGbP82BZFtZ1ZX8LbNsmm33fh2EYWJaFPfH1BiIIAmiahmma2NMg4hYgoiiCqqpo25b99ewtQBRFwZOrqmJPk0kycP3nuq6h6zrKsmQvJgsRMtB1HUzTRNM07H\/xoKXveyiKAtd1+Ul5nr8pTVPu4QDdMM8zwjBElmVIkgRxHHMVezobx\/HVDjwBP7YQLmkjHg4AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"12\" \/> <\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">DPC = 20&deg;. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>120\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>140\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>160\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>100\u00b0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Harish bought a certain number of mangoes from the market and distributed them among his three sons. To his eldest son, he gave one more than half the total number of mangoes. To his second son, he gave two more than one-third the number of mangoes that remained after giving to his first son. To his third son, he gave three more than one-fourth of the remaining mangoes. Now, after giving to his third son, if he was left with exactly three mangoes, find the number of mangoes that he gave to his first son.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>17\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>32\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the value of m, if 2<sup>(<\/sup><sup>2<\/sup><sup>m<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>-<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>6<\/sup><sup>)<\/sup><sup>(<\/sup><sup>m<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>+<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>1<\/sup><sup>)<\/sup><sup> <\/sup> = 4<sup>(<\/sup><sup>m<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>+<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>2<\/sup><sup>)<\/sup><sup>(<\/sup><sup>m<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>-<\/sup><sup> <\/sup><sup>3<\/sup><sup>)<\/sup><b>.<\/b>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"3","CORRECT_ANSWER":"3","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the remainder when 7! is divided by 8?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"0","CORRECT_ANSWER":"0","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>How many of the following statements are definitely true or definitely false?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<ol><li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost of A and E together is less than that of B and D together.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost of D is more than B.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The difference between the costs of E and D is more than the difference between the costs of A and B.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The ratio of the cost of A to the cost of D is less than 0.6.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<\/ol>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"5507","EASSY_DETAILS":"<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i><i><b> <\/b><\/i>Answer the questions on the basis of the information given below.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">A, B, C, D and E are five cars such that the price of C is twice that of A and the price of E is one-third that of B. The ratio of the price of D and that of C is 4 : 5.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","ESSAY_NAME":"D-X) Test name AIMCAT1922"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":"","ESSAY_NAME":""},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>How many of the following statements, when considered independently, will be sufficient to find the ratio of the cost of A to the cost of E?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<ol><li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The difference between the costs of B and C is same as the difference between the costs of \nA and E.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The ratio of the cost of A and that of B is 2 : 1.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost of E and D together is equal to the cost of A and B together.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<li style='vertical-align:middle; padding-bottom:10px;list-style-type:upper-roman;'><span><p style='vertical-align:text-top; display:inline-block;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The sum of the costs of B and A together is twice that of C and E together.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span><\/li>\n<\/ol>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"5507","EASSY_DETAILS":"<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i><i><b> <\/b><\/i>Answer the questions on the basis of the information given below.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\"> <font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">A, B, C, D and E are five cars such that the price of C is twice that of A and the price of E is one-third that of B. The ratio of the price of D and that of C is 4 : 5.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","ESSAY_NAME":"D-X) Test name AIMCAT1922"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":"","ESSAY_NAME":""},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>When Santosh asked Lalitha what her weight was, she said, \u201cThe difference between your weight and my weight is more than your weight. Also, five times your weight is more than twice my weight\u201d. If Santosh weighs 40 kg and Lalitha\u2019s weight (in kg) is an integer, which of the following could be the maximum possible difference in their weights? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>99 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>59 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>48 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>58 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the profit\/loss percentage when an item purchased for Rs.48 is sold for Rs.56?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>13.67% profit\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>15.33% loss\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>16.67% profit\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>19.33% loss\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>For the annual day celebrations in a school, nine different cultural activities were organised. For operational reasons, the class-teacher of class V ensured that the number of students from her class taking part in each of the nine cultural activities was the same. It was observed that each student from class V took part in either exactly five or none of the cultural activities. If there are a total of 61 students in class V, the minimum number of students of that class who did not participate in any of the cultural activities is \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The volume of a cylinder is 4312 cm<sup>3<\/sup>. If the radius of the cylinder is twice its height, find the height of the cylinder. (Assume  <img Width='47' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAC4AAAAgCAYAAABts0pHAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANVSURBVFhH7ZhLKLRRGMfHLYkiZYGSclm4bpQNNjOxlhJlzQJZ2FiRe0lTJCuUcStRyiULyoKwEitESVi632\/\/r\/8zx\/uNmTGLbxrvWXy\/eur9n3Ma\/\/O+zznnOSwwiY+PD6ysrKCxsRG9vb1oaGhAa2srnp+f1Qjg5OQEnZ2d6OjoQHt7O2pra7G7uyt9phl\/eXlBWFgYhoaG8Pb2hu3tbURGRsJut6sRQGlpKQoLC3F3d4ebmxtYrVZkZmZKn2nGb29vMTs7q5STvLw8ZGVlKQUsLS3h9PRUKWBqagoWiwWXl5fmGfdGYmIiqqqqlPKEacOvxHTSxvj09DSCg4O\/vWFXHh4eEBUVhZ6eHtFaGD86OhJTCwsLqsWTkpISVFZWKqWBceZrfHw8+vr6VIsn1dXVyM\/PV8qJ6cZpqKmpSSknn5+f6gno7+9HamoqXl9fVYsTU403NzfDZrMpBdnyampq8Pj4KHp\/f1++xvHxsWjCBbq+vm6eceY1t7a4uDgkJycjKSkJMTExYpRvnAcUJ8Ux6enp0s+g3tvbM884T0XuJJOTkxgdHZUYHx\/H5uam9L+\/v2Nubk7GfPUzZmZmZFKm5\/i\/8t\/4b2MY52Jh3h0cHODw8FBOMLZRsyDSDQtNVlRUyIqNjo5GWloaUlJSEB4eLrUDtet2RDihtrY2n8GFFEgsy8vL2NjYwNjYmBwG9\/f3ODs7k21nZGRENFexKzs7OygvL\/cZrK1\/gmUsf9efMFKFJWNRUZE8s\/4NCgqSrSgQLC4uypf0JwzjfLsFBQXyfHV1JcY5GW9cXFxIn69YXV1Voz1hLc61408YxltaWoxChsaZKj+98a2tLbmZ+Ir6+no1OjAYxlky5ubmyvP19bUYHx4elurNtejRBcN4WVmZcfvgYuR9j9eogYGBXzPOtcU0cg+2u2MYdzdHfX5+rlTg4d\/LyclBSEgIQkNDJSIiIhAbG4uJiQk16i+GcbPhgZeQkCAXCm4UjO7ubqkeuebc0cr4\/Py8Uk54FtTV1Sn1HW2Mu8NNgV\/A\/dT+QlvjXV1dKC4uVsoTLY0\/PT3JTWhtbU21eKKlcf4vMSMjQynvaGmclarD4VDKO9oZ572TezcrSF9oZzw7OxuDg4NK\/QTwBwvRYuOGzjIdAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/> ) \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4.5 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3.5 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9 cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The average score of a cricketer in a certain number of innings is 44. If he then played another eight innings, in which he scored 97, 3, 23, 0, 68, 40, 50 and 71 runs respectively, which of the following statements is true regarding his new average score in all the innings together?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The new average is more than the old average.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The new average is less than the old average.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The new average is the same as the old average.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot conclude any of the above unless we know the initial number of innings played.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A certain number of children are standing in a row, all of them facing North. There are twice as many girls in the row as there are boys. From the west end of the row, Ajay is 8<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> among the boys and 17<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> among all the children. From the east end of the row he is 20<sup>t<\/sup><sup>h<\/sup> among all the children. How many boys are there to the right of Ajay?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>16\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"}}